WENDY POST, DNP, MSN, RN

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

High performance, versatile and commercially astute forward thinker offering a career of impressive successes across the healthcare quality, operational leadership, nursing education, maternal child health and patient safety continuum. Contributing comprehensive organizational experience forged in the environment of patient safety, performance improvement, clinical education and professional practice. Particularly detail driven and analytical with diplomatic perspective in problem solving. Talented negotiator with keen cultural awareness. Experienced in Healthcare Quality, Nursing Education, Program Implementation and Mentorship

*

CONTACT



301-310-1906



GERMDETECTIVE@ICLOUD.COM



SEVERN, MARYLAND



Linkedin.com/in/ WendyPost

EDUCATION

The George Washington University PhD in Nursing, DC, in progress (NIH scholar)

Georgetown University Executive Masters in Clinical Quality, Safety and Leadership, DC, 2022

University of North Carolina

Doctorate in Nursing Practice, NC 2019

Columbia University
Certificate in Narrative Medicine NY, 2018

American Sentinel University

Master of Science in Nursing, focus in
Infection Control and Epidmiology CO, 2017

University of Southern California
Bachelor of Science In Nursing, CA, 2000

EXPERTISE

Clinical Education/Adjunct Clinical Faculty
Infectious Disease & Epidemiology
Regulatory Compliance/Risk Mitigation
Adept in Patient Safety/Process
Improvement/Superior Problem Solving
Lean Six Sigma - Green Belt Certification
Progressive /FEMA Emergency
Management

EXPERIENCE

MEDSTAR SOUTHERN MARYLAND HOSPITAL CENTER

Women and Infant Services Director- 09/2022-present

Responsible for the oversight of the Perinatal Department inclusive of the Special Care Nursery, Postpartum, Labor and Delivery and Antepartum Units; Awarded Baby Friendly designation after November 2022 survey; 84 direct reports with budget and staffing oversight

STATE OF MARYLAND: OFFICE OF HEALTHCARE QUALITY

Health Facilities Nurse Surveyor- Hospital Division/Columbia, MD/ 01-2020-07/2022

Conducts on site surveys of providers, regulated by the Office of Health Care Quality, and determines their compliance with federal and or state regulations. This position is an integral part of the OHCQ's mission, which is to protect the health and safety of the citizens of Maryland, as well as ensure that there is public confidence in the health care and community service delivery systems.

KAISER PERMANENTE- REGIONAL OFFICE MID ATLANTIC STATES

Perinatal Nurse Educator-3/2003-present

Serves as a clinical leader, consultant and educator for clinical practice. Provides support for implementing and maintaining clinical excellence specifically standards and competencies of the clinical staff. The Clinical Educator assists Senior Clinical Practice

Leaders and the Regional Nurse Executive with efforts to ensure all processes and systems meet the quality, regulatory, certifying, and licensing standards for nursing are in place and assists with monitoring compliance with those standards.

PROGRAM MANAGER: CLINICAL EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL PRACTICE

Bon Secours Health System Corporate Office/Mariottsville, MD/06/2018-03/2019
Collaborates with clinical executives across settings in organizational activities intended to ensure excellence in patient care delivery. Responsible for providing innovative leadership and serves as a culture and change management strategist to advance the practice of professional nursing and Clinical Transformation within Bon Secours Health System. This includes establishing partnerships, linkages, and collaboration among nursing, physician and organizational leaders, advanced practice nurses, nurse educators, researchers, and affiliated academic institutions. The Director serves as a facilitator for the shared decision-making process, and provides leadership for utilization of best practice evidence, scholarly work in nursing, and advancement of professional practice utilizing the ANCC Magnet/Pathways to Excellence Program framework.

SENIOR SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT/SENIOR CONSULTANT ADVISOR

United States Department of Health and Human Services- Office of the Secretary for Preparedness and Response; Office of Policy and Planning Medical Countermeasure Utilization and Response Integration

Washington D.C./2017-present/Consultation and Advisory capacity

DIRECTOR OF INFECTION PREVENTION/PATIENT SAFETY CHAIR

St. Agnes Hospital / Baltimore, MD / 10/2016-07/2018

Patient safety chair with responsibility for effective patient safety and risk mitigation related Infection Prevention and Control departmental alliances; responsible for establishing mission, vision, planning, direction, assessment, leadership and fiscal responsibility for key vital hospital committees, taskforces, and change packages.

Vaulted quality of patient care 25% higher by strengthening relationships with surgeons and improved feedback from all stakeholders through increased executive leadership's participation in key roles throughout the hospital, interdisciplinary departments and the health enterprise Invested in key publications directly related to hospital acquired infection prevention and CDC pilot hospital studies (Pediatric VAE) fostering standardization of care and epidemiological related guidelines for the 2018 fiscal year

Primary Liason for for Hospital Epidemiology and Patient Safety dashboard; departmental administrator for electronic event reporting system; coordinated patient narratives for patient safety committee

Liaisoned 'The Safe Surgery Initiave' with Surgery Chairman to promote strategies and processes to decrease surgical infections by application

Recruited MSN commissioned staff throughout the department

Co-strategized, with no downtime whatsoever, the task of synchronizing systems of multiple facilities-impacting over 100 staff members and 75 physicians

HONORS/AWARDS

Sigma honor society- Inducted as Nurse Leader, 2016

Golden Key International Honor Society, 2015

U.S. Department of Health and **Human Services ASPR Tracie SME** Cadre Member, 2016

Phi Kappa Phi Honor Society Member

ASSOCIATESHIPS

AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION (APHA)

SOCIETY OF HEALTHCARE EPIDEMIOLOGY OF AMERICA (SHEA)

ASSOCIATION FOR PROFESSIONALS IN INFECTION CONTROL AND HOSPITAL **EPIDEMIOLOGY (APIC)**

NATIONAL ASSOCIATION FOR HEALTHCARE OUALITY (NAHO)

AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR PROFESSIONALS IN PATIENT SAFETY (ASPPS)

AMERICAN NURSES ASSOCIATION (ANA)

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

State of Maryland Maternal Mortality Task Force Member 2022- present (four year term)

Trinity University

Adjunct Clinical Faculty: Maternal Child 2018-present

Anne Arundel Community College Adjunct Clinical Faculty: Maternal Child LPN and AND programs 2019-2020

West Georgia Technical College Adjunct Clinical Faculty: Maternal Child Health (two consecutive positions) 2013-2015 (Fall Semesters only)

Kaiser Permanente-West Los Angeles Clinical RN IV-Labor and Delivery/ED 2003-2007

California Hospital Medical Center **Clinical RN-High Risk Labor and Delivery** 2000-2003

SENIOR OUALITY MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST-CORPORATE OFFICE

Piedmont Vinings / Atlanta, GA / 03/2013-10/2016

Tasked with revitalizing, managing and standardizing daily operations of over 100 outpatient clinics across remote areas of Georgia servicing end to end patient care across a range of specializations including OBGYN, oncology, urgent care, surgery and cancer centers.

- Orchestrated the recruitment and management of an outpatient specific patient safety team within a rigid 6 week timeline, performed comprehensive due diligence in securing physician partnerships
- Restored one facilty from a position of immenent license revocation to that of total compliance and a 3 year full independent accreditation within one
- Catapulted monthly case volume from 300 to 650+ procedures
- Standardized cleaning and disinfection practices within all outpatient locations within all outpatient locations with an alliance partnership of CSP.

CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL AND PREVENTION-INSTRUCTOR/CURRICULUM DEVELOPER: EBOLA RESPONSE TRAINING

Domestic Preparedness / FEMA Headquarters / 11/2014-03/2015 Entrusted with designing and developing curriculum for U.S clinicians deploying to West Africa to work in Ebola virus treatment units (ETUs); created the physcial architecture of a mock ETU on the FEMA traning site with tabletip demonstrations and donning and doffing full PPE in emergency situations; scenerios were published and photographed through the CDC and made available on the public website: https://www.cdc.gov/vhf/ebola/hcp/safety-training-course/training-toolkit.html

- Assisted the U.S. army and public health service leaders in donning and doffing procedures while on military aircraft ('airborne'); provided valued standard of practice procedures in emergency situations; recommended utilization of PAPRs for military missions in collaboration with education and demonstration.
- Fortified market supremacy in Epidemiological emergencies by caring for a humanitarian physician; interfaced with public health officials to streamline processes and coordinate best practice models for hospitals worldwide
- Liased with hospitals and major health associations, such as Johns Hopkins, NIH, and World Health Organization to relay emerging information on Ebola to create comprehensive releases for public health initiatives

OUALITY NURSE CONSULTANT: INFECTION PREVENTION

Emory Healthcare / Atlanta, GA / 01/2013-03/2014 (two consecutive positions) Championed all quality management activities (with concentration on two core measures: immunizations and sepsis); JCAHO compliance, risk management and patient safety, performance improvement, and infection control. Developed strategic plans and policies for improved quality throughout the hospital

- Worked with top management to ensure compliance with regulatory agencies
- Managed a departmental sub-function within a broader departmental function
- Created functional strategies and specific objectives for the sub-function in developing budgets, policies, and procedures to support the functional patient safety and quality infrastructure
- Reviewed and corrected contracted data abstractors in two concentrated core measures

LABOR AND DELIVERY RN-PER DIEM INTERIM DIRECTOR OF INFECTION PREVENTION AND PATIENT SAFETY

Atlanta Medical Center/Atlanta, GA/03/2012-11-2013 (post OB unit closure) Placed emphasis on quality while handling clinical operations within two hospital campuses; standing in as the interim director of the infection prevention department prior to promotion to service at Emory Healthcare

Used sound judgement to develop over 75 policies and procedures to mitigate risks facing infection control and prevention, exceeding expectations set by the JC, CMS and state/local public health stakeholders